ACWA Hyman Blumberg Photographs 6015 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ACWA Hyman Blumberg Photographs
1930-1956
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA)
Blumberg, Hyman
6015 P
3.33 cubic feet
2.3 linear ft.
Photographs, memorabilia.
7581991
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, January 20, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, July 25, 2016
Biographical / Historical
The Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, led by Sidney Hillman for thirty years, was known for its support for 'social unionism' and progressive political causes. It also helped found the Congress of Industrial Organizations. In 1976 they merged with Textile Workers Union of America to form the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union, which merged with the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union in 1995 and created the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) merged with UNITE in 2004 to create the new union UNITE HERE. A bitter internal dispute in 2009 resulted in a new union being formed, Workers United, the majority UNITE joined with some of the unhappy HERE locals. Bruce Raynor, former UNITE president oversaw the new union.
Scope and Contents
Many convention badges, lots of newspaper clippings deteriorating conditions. 1? In hebrew. Photos are in plastic covered pages of albums or rolled up due to lack of support. Many books are duplicates of library mateirals and Center rare items. Few are novel additions.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5619: ACWA Records 5619 mf: ACWA Records Parts 1-3 on Microfilm 5868 mf: Joseph Schlossberg Additional Papers on Microfilm 5110: Jacob Billikopf New York City Men's Clothing Industry Arbiration Case Files 5670: ACWA Organizer Ida Alter Diaries 5674 OHM: ACWA Master Tapes of Interviews with Retirees 5674 OHT: ACWA Transcripts of Interviews with Retirees 5744: ACTWU Newsclipping Files regarding J.P. Stevens Boycott 5743 P: ACWA Photographs 5107: Decision of the Boards Regarding Hart, Schaffner & Marx, Chicago Industrial Federation of Clothing Manufacturers 5665 mf: ACTWU Fall River Local Minute Books on Microfilm 6015: ACWA Hyman Blumberg Records 6015 MB: ACWA Hyman Blumberg Memorabilia
Blumberg, Hyman, 1885-1968; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America--Photographs
7581991
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America - 13th Biennial Silver Jubilee Convention, New York, N.Y., May 13-24, 1940, 1914-1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Program and Handbook; 50 black and white photographs [contents of a photograph album]
- To Bessie and Hyman Blumberg, Tenth Anniversary Celebration of MD, VA. PA. Regional Joint Board, November 6, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  16 photographs; [photograph album contents]
- Hyman Blumberg (Box 2, Folder 3)
  43 photographs; [photograph album contents]
- Testimonial Dinner to Hyman Blumberg, Webster Hall, March 15, 1943, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  33 photographs; [photograph album contents]
- Pennsylvania Joint Board A.C.W.A., Union Center Dedication, August 27th, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  48 photographs; [photograph album contents]
- Surprise Birthday Dinner in the Honor of Her Husband Hyman Blumberg; Picture Album Presented to Bess Blumberg of the December 12th, 1947, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Program; 23 photographs; [photograph album contents]
- Political Campaigns, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  69 photographs; [contents of photograph album]
- Presented by the MD., VA., PA., Regional Joint Board, A.C.W. of A. on the Occasion of Bess and Hyman Blumberg's Golden Wedding Anniversary (Box 3, Folder 1)
  27 photographs; [photograph album contents]
- Testimonial Dinner in Honor of the Birthday of Alex Cohen; Tendered by Joint Board of Shirt, Leisurewear, Robe, Glove and Rainwear Workers Union ACWA, Hotel Pennsylvania, Feb. 20, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  1 photograph
- Annual Dinner, American Labor Party-Kings County in Honor of Hon. Henry A. Wallace, Hotel St. George, Dec. 4, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Testimonial Dinner Tendered to J.B.S. Hardman on the Occasion of his Sixtieth Birthday, Hotel Brevoort, Nov. 17, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Testimonial Banquet, Tendered by the Lapel Makers and Pairers Union, Local 161, ACWA in Honor of the Manager, Anthony V. Froise, Webster Hall -- Nov. 17th, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- South Jersey Joint Executive Board, Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, Ritz-Carlton Hotel - Atlantic City, N.J., November 5th, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- 25th Anniversary Dinner Dace, New York Clothing Cutters Union, Hotel St. George, Feb. 26, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  1 photograph; [in mylar sleeve, flip side of 6015 P box 3, ff 6]
- New York State Amalgamated Conference, Hotel Statler, Buffalo, New York, September 14, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  1 photograph; [in mylar sleeve; flip side of box 3, ff5]
- New York State Amalgamated Conference, Hotel Statler, Buffalo, New York, September 14, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  1 photograph; [in mylar sleeve, flip side of Box 3, ff4]
- Testimonial Luncheon in Honor of Mayor William O'Dwyer, tendered by Business and Labor of the City of New York, Hotel Commodore, March 31, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  1 photograph; [in mylar sleeve, flip side of Box 3, ff3]
- Dinner Tendered Mayor-Elect Fiorello M. LaGuardia by Italian Dress Makers Union Local No. 89, Cloaks and Suits Local No. 48 and Amalgamated Workers No. 63, 142, 162 and 198 - Riccardi's Restaurant, Dec. 22, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  1 photograph; [in mylar sleeve, flip side of Box 3, ff12]
- Committee for Industrial Organization, CIO, President Hotel, Oct. 1937, Atlantic City (Box 3, Folder 12)
  1 photograph; [in mylar sleeve, flip side of Box 3, ff11]
- Jacob Potofsky photograph (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Unlabelled photographs (Box 3, Folder 14)
  2 photographs - back to back in a mylar sleeve
- G.E.B. Wives' Luncheon, 20th Biennial Convention, Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, Washington, D.C., May 21-25, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Testimonial Dinner to Joseph A. Salerno, Copley Plaza Hotel, Boston, Mass., March 12th, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Special Luncheon to Joint Board and Local Officers, Shop Chairmen, Shop Committee Members, and Employers by the Laundry Workers Joint Board, ACWA, Hotel Capitol, April 17, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Baltimore Delegation to the Fifth Biennial Convention, ACWA, Chicago, May 8-13, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Baltimore Delegation to the Fifth Biennial Convention ACWA, Chicago, May 8-13, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Emerson Hotel Baltimore, Hyman Blumberg, Abe Chatman, Sol Brandzel (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Women Delegates at the Sixth Biennial Convention of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, Philadelphia Pa, May 12th to 17th, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Women Delegates at the Sixth Biennial Convention of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, Philadelphia, PA, May 12th to 17th, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Italian Delegates at the Sixth Biennial Convention of the amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, Philadelphia, PA, May 12th to 17th, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Banquet in Honor of General Executive Board ACWA, Morrison Hotel, March 17, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- American Labor Press Ass'n. Conference on Winning the War and Winning Peace, Hotel Commodore, Feb. 21, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- 20th Biennial Convention, Amalgamated Clothing Workers, AFL-CIO, Washington, DC, May 21-25, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  33 photographs
- Birthday Luncheon in Honor of Bess Blumberg given by Women's Aux. Local 324 ACWA, Feb. 15, 1949 - White House Restaurant (Box 4, Folder 2)
  8 photographs; [photograph album contents]
- 11 panoramic photos (Box 5, Folder 1)
  18 Bi-Annual Convention Oct-1914, Nashville, Tenn.; Second Annual Convention, Labor's Non-Partisan League, Willard Hotel, March 8-9, 1937, Washington, D.C.; Eighth Biennial Convention of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, Cincinnati, Ohio - May 14-19, 1928; Eleventh Biennial Convention of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, Cleveland Ohio, May 25-30, 1936; Banquet in Honor of the General Executive Board A.C.W. of A., Toronto Labor Lyceum, Oct. 15th, 1927; 17th Biennial convention, the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, Cleveland, Ohio, May 15-19, 1950; 4th Biennial Convention, Amalgamated Clothing Workers of AmericaBoston, Mass.. May 10, 1920; Sixth Biennial Convention of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, Philadelphia Penna, May 12th to 17th, 1924; Sixth Biennial Convention of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, Philadelphia Penna, May 12th to 17th, 1924; Fifth Biennial Convention, Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, Chicago, May 8-13, 1922 (2 copies)
- Ninth Biennial Convention of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, Toronto, May 12 to 17, 1930 (2 copies) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  2 oversize photos